<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://yangfengstat/yangfengstat.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://yangfengstat/yangfengstat.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-05-20T03:03:30+00:00</updated><id>https://yangfengstat/yangfengstat.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>Professor Yang Feng from New York University, working on machine learning, social networks, nonparametrics, and causal inference. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">My Spanish Learning Journey</title><link href="https://yangfengstat/yangfengstat.github.io/blog/2024/spanish-learning-journey/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Spanish Learning Journey"/><published>2024-12-04T17:23:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-04T17:23:00+00:00</updated><id>https://yangfengstat/yangfengstat.github.io/blog/2024/spanish-learning-journey</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://yangfengstat/yangfengstat.github.io/blog/2024/spanish-learning-journey/"><![CDATA[<h3 id="celebrating-4-years-of-learning-spanish-">Celebrating 4 Years of Learning Spanish 🎉</h3> <p>Today marks a special milestone: four years since I began learning Spanish through Duolingo!</p> <p><img src="/assets/img/duolingo-4years.PNG" alt="Duolingo" width="200"/></p> <p>Spanish is the third most spoken language in the world, following English and Chinese. Learning it has been a challenging but immensely rewarding journey. In this post, I’ll reflect on the tools, strategies, and resources that have shaped my progress from a beginner to a confident intermediate speaker.</p> <hr/> <h3 id="starting-small-duolingo-and-the-power-of-habit"><strong>Starting Small: Duolingo and the Power of Habit</strong></h3> <p>My Spanish journey began with Duolingo. Its gamified approach made learning fun and unintimidating. Spending just 10 minutes a day on short lessons became a sustainable habit. While Duolingo is a great way to get started and build vocabulary, I quickly realized that advancing in a language requires more structured and immersive learning.<br/> <img src="/assets/img/duolingo-15mins.jpeg" alt="Duolingo" width="300"/></p> <hr/> <h3 id="going-deeper-structured-study-with-books"><strong>Going Deeper: Structured Study with Books</strong></h3> <p>To solidify my understanding of grammar and expand my vocabulary, I turned to textbooks. Here are some that have been particularly impactful:</p> <ol> <li><strong>Exploraciones (3rd Edition)</strong> by Mary Ann Blitt and Margarita Casas – A fantastic resource for beginners, offering clear explanations and engaging exercises.</li> <li><strong>Easy Spanish Step-by-Step</strong> by Barbara Bregstein – This book provided a systematic approach to mastering Spanish grammar, making complex concepts digestible.</li> <li><strong>Portales 2</strong> – An excellent intermediate-level book for broadening language skills.</li> <li><strong>Intrigas: Advanced Spanish Through Literature and Film (3rd Edition)</strong> – This introduced me to Spanish literature and films, enriching my cultural understanding.</li> <li><strong>Revista, 6th Edition: Conversación sin barreras</strong> – Focused on improving conversational skills through thought-provoking content.</li> </ol> <p>Each book added layers of depth to my learning, helping me progress beyond the basics.</p> <hr/> <h3 id="listening-spanish-podcasts"><strong>Listening: Spanish Podcasts</strong></h3> <p>Listening to Spanish became an essential part of my routine, and podcasts were a convenient way to immerse myself in the language. Two podcasts stood out:</p> <ul> <li><strong>Coffee Break Spanish</strong> – Perfect for beginners and intermediate learners, this podcast taught me practical phrases and grammar tips. I often listened while driving, walking, or doing household chores.</li> <li><strong>Duolingo Spanish Podcast</strong> – This storytelling-based podcast caters to intermediate learners. Its mix of English and Spanish narration helped me follow along while gradually increasing my listening comprehension.</li> </ul> <hr/> <h3 id="watching-spanish-tv-shows-and-movies"><strong>Watching: Spanish TV Shows and Movies</strong></h3> <p>To truly immerse myself, I started watching Spanish TV shows and movies. These not only improved my listening skills but also gave me a window into Spanish-speaking cultures.</p> <ul> <li><strong>Favorite TV Show:</strong> <ul> <li><strong>La Casa de Papel (Money Heist)</strong> – The gripping plot and brilliant acting made it impossible to stop watching.</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Movies I Loved:</strong> <ul> <li><strong>El Laberinto del Fauno (Pan’s Labyrinth)</strong> – A hauntingly beautiful fantasy film.</li> <li><strong>Tambien la Lluvia (Even the Rain)</strong> – A thought-provoking exploration of history and politics.</li> <li><strong>Roma</strong> – An Academy Award-winning masterpiece.</li> <li><strong>Contratiempo (The Invisible Guest)</strong> – A thrilling mystery that keeps you guessing.</li> <li><strong>El Cuerpo (The Body)</strong> – Another suspenseful gem.</li> <li><strong>La Lengua de Las Mariposas (Butterfly’s Tongue)</strong> – A poignant story of innocence and loss.</li> <li><strong>Como Agua Para Chocolate (Like Water for Chocolate)</strong> – A heartwarming tale of love and tradition.</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <p>These films and shows not only improved my vocabulary but also introduced me to different accents and dialects in the Spanish-speaking world.</p> <hr/> <h3 id="reflections-and-whats-next"><strong>Reflections and What’s Next</strong></h3> <p>Looking back, learning Spanish has been more than just acquiring a new language—it’s been a journey of personal growth, cultural appreciation, and expanding my horizons. From daily Duolingo lessons to diving into literature, podcasts, and films, every step has brought me closer to fluency.</p> <p>As I celebrate this four-year milestone, I’m excited about what lies ahead. My goal is to continue improving my speaking skills through conversation practice and to explore more complex texts and media in Spanish.</p> <p>To anyone considering learning a new language, I wholeheartedly encourage you to take the plunge. The journey is as rewarding as the destination.</p> <p>¡Hasta luego!</p> <hr/>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="spanish"/><category term="spanish,"/><category term="language-learning,"/><category term="personal-growth"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Reflecting on four years of learning Spanish]]></summary></entry></feed>